ebaystores.com.au 2019-12-31

# User Privacy Notice | eBay

This User Privacy Notice applies to your use of this website and all eBay applications, services (including payment services), products and tools (collectively the "Services"), regardless of how you access or use these Services, including access via mobile devices and apps.

### Learn more

This User Privacy Notice also applies if explicit reference is made to it via a link or in a similar manner, e.g. on websites of partners on which Services from eBay are offered.

We may change this User Privacy Notice at any time by posting the revised User Privacy Notice on this website and indicating the effective date of the revised User Privacy Notice. You will be notified of any material changes to this User Privacy Notice via [Messages \- opens in new window or tab](https://mesg.ebay.com.au/mesgweb/ViewMessages/0) in My eBay and/or by email.

## 2\. Controller

Which eBay company is responsible for the collection and processing of your personal data in connection with the provision of the Services depends on how you use our Services.

### 2.1 Use of the Services

The following eBay company is responsible for the collection and processing of your personal data in connection with the provision of our Services (except payment services for sellers, see below under Use of the payment services for sellers), depending on the region in which you are located:

  * **USA:** eBay Inc., 2025 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95125, USA
  * **Canada:** eBay Canada Limited, 500 King Street West, Suite 200, Toronto, ON M5V 1L9, Canada
  * **EU:** eBay GmbH, Albert-Einstein-Ring 2-6, 14532 Kleinmachnow, Germany. If you use the eBay Customer Guarantee offered in France, Italy or Spain, eBay Services S.à r.l., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg is responsible for data processing with regard to this particular service.
  * **United Kingdom:** eBay (UK) Limited, 1 More London Place, London, SE1 2AF, United Kingdom
  * **India:** eBay Singapore Services Private Limited, 10 Collyer Quay, #10-01 Ocean Financial Centre, Singapore 049315
  * **For all other countries:** eBay Marketplaces GmbH, Helvetiastrasse 15/17, 3005 Bern, Switzerland

### 2.2 Use of the payment services for sellers

The following eBay company is responsible for the collection and processing of your personal data in connection with the provision of our payment services to sellers, depending on which region you are located in and whether we provide our payment services there:

  * **USA:** eBay Commerce Inc., 2025 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95125, USA
  * **EU:** eBay S.à r.l., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg
  * **Canada:** eBay Canada Limited., 500 King Street West, Suite 200, Toronto, ON M5V 1L9, Canada
  * **UK:** eBay (UK) Limited 5 New Street Square., London, EC4A 3TW, United Kingdom
  * **In a country within the EU (except the United Kingdom):** eBay GmbH., Albert-Einstein-Ring 2-6, 14532 Kleinmachnow, Germany
  * **If you reside in any other country:** eBay Marketplaces GmbH, Helvetiastrasse 15/17, 3005 Bern, Switzerland.

### 2.3 Disclosure to other entities overseas

Your personal data may be disclosed to recipients located overseas including but not limited to: India, Philippines, Switzerland, UK, and USA.

## 3\.  Data protection officer and contact

In those countries where we are required to do so by law, we have appointed data protection officers to oversee the protection of your personal data. If you have any questions about this User Privacy Notice or about data protection at eBay in general, you can contact the data protection officer responsible for your country at any time. You will find the contact details of your data protection officer in the [list of our data protection officers \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/privacy-notice/data-protection-officer-contacts/) in our eBay Privacy Center.

Furthermore, if you have any questions or complaints regarding this User Privacy Notice, our global privacy standards (see section **6.1 Data transfers to eBay Inc. corporate family members** under section 6\. International data transfers below) or our handling of personal data, you can also contact the eBay Privacy Team or the controller who is responsible for the processing of your personal data at any time (for further information, see section 2\. Controller above). This applies regardless of whether we have appointed a data protection officer in your country or not. You can find all necessary information and contact details including a [contact form \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/privacy-contact/) in our [eBay Privacy Center \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/).

## 4\. What personal data we collect and process

We collect your personal data when you use our Services, create a new eBay account, provide us with information via a web form, add or update information in your eBay account, participate in online community discussions or otherwise interact with us. We also collect personal data from other sources (such as other eBay Inc. corporate family members or credit agencies or bureaus).

### Learn more

In total, we collect the following personal data:

### 4.1 Personal data you provide when using our Services or creating an eBay account

  * Data that identifies you, such as your name, address, telephone numbers or email addresses, your username, or your VAT identification number that you provide when setting up your eBay account or at a later date, and additional identification data and tax identification numbers that you provide when using our payment services as a seller.
  * Data regarding bids, purchases, or sales that you provide in a transaction.
  * Content that you share with other users through our messaging tools (see **Filtering of messages sent via our messaging tools** under section 11\. Other important information regarding data protection for more information).
  * Financial information (e.g. credit card and account numbers, payment details) in connection with a transaction.
  * Delivery, billing, and other information you provide in connection with the purchase or delivery of an item, as well as information required for customs clearance (such as tax identification numbers or other identification numbers) and relevant delivery information (such as shipment numbers and tracking information) if sent through one of our programs.
  * In some cases: age, gender, country of birth, nationality, employment status, family status, interests and preferences.
  * You may provide us with additional information through a web form or by updating or adding information to your eBay account, by participating in community discussions, member chats, enquiries, dispute resolution, customer service calls recorded with your consent, or if you contact us for any other reason regarding our Services.
  * Other data that we are required or entitled by applicable law to collect and process and that we need for your authentication or identification, or for the verification of the data we collect.

### 4.2 Personal data we collect automatically when you use our Services or create an eBay account

  * Data that is generated as part of one of your transactions (bids, purchases, sales) or that is linked to your eBay account as a result of a transaction in which you are involved, such as transaction amounts, time and location of transactions and payment methods.
  * Data that is generated through your other actions when you use our Services and which is linked to your eBay account, e.g. when you place items in your shopping cart, place items on the Watchlist, save sellers, searches or interests, or follow users.
  * Data regarding all other interactions with our Services, your advertising preferences, and your communications with us.
  * Location data, including the location data of your mobile device. Please note that for most mobile devices, you can manage or disable the use of location services for all applications in the settings menu of your mobile device.
  * Computer and connection information, such as statistics regarding your use of services from eBay, information on data traffic to and from websites, referral URL, information on advertisements, your IP address, your access times, your browser history data, your language settings and your weblog information.

### 4.3 Personal data we collect in connection with the use of cookies and similar technologies

We use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to collect data while you use our Services. We collect this data from the devices (including mobile devices) with which you use our Services. The data collected includes the following usage- and device-related information:

  * Data about the pages you visit, the access time, frequency and duration of visits, the links on which you click and other actions you take as part of your use of our Services and in advertising and email content.
  * Data about your activities and interactions with our advertising partners including data about the advertisements you were shown, how often they were shown, when and where they were shown, and whether you took any action, such as clicking on an advertisement or making a purchase.
  * Your user segment.
  * Model or device type, operating system and version, browser type and settings, device ID or individual device identifier, advertisement ID, individual device token, and cookie-related data (e.g. cookie ID).
  * The IP address from which your device accesses the Services.
  * Location data, including the location data of your mobile device. Please note that most mobile devices allow you to manage or disable the use of location services for all applications in the settings menu.

For more information about our use of these technologies and your choices, see Cookies & similar technologies.

### 4.4 Personal data from other sources

We also collect personal data about you from other sources and from third parties to the extent permitted by applicable law. In particular, this includes the following data:

  * Data from public sources (e.g. demographic data)
  * Data from credit agencies or bureaus (e.g. credit reports/checks)
  * Data from data providers (e.g. demographic, interest-based and online advertising related data).

With regard to our payment services for sellers: data from government or other sources concerning any previous convictions of the respective seller, to the extent permitted by applicable law. We combine or connect the personal data we collect from you with data from these other sources. Where personal data is disclosed to us by third parties, we take steps to confirm that the information has been collected with your consent and/or that these third parties are otherwise legally permitted to disclose your personal data to us. We also receive access to personal data about you from other members of the [eBay Inc. corporate family \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/our-businesses/).

### 4.5 Social network data you share with us

  * We allow you to share personal data with social networks, to use social networks to create an eBay account or to link your eBay account to a social network. These social networks may automatically provide us with access to certain personal data they have stored about you (e.g. content you have viewed or enjoyed, information about the advertisements you have been shown or clicked on, etc.). You can determine the personal data that we can access through the privacy settings of each social network.
  * If you give us access to video content pages, your grant of access is your consent that we may, for at least two years, or until you withdraw your consent or are no longer connected to the social network, share with and collect from social networks information regarding your viewing of videos.
  * We may also use plug-ins or other technologies from various social networks. If you click on a link displayed through a social network plug-in, you voluntarily connect to that social network.

## 5\. Purposes and legal basis for data processing and categories of recipients

We process your personal data for various purposes and pursuant to various legal bases. We process your personal data primarily to provide and improve our Services, to provide you with a personalised user experience on this website, to contact you about your eBay account and our Services, to provide customer service, to provide you with personalised advertising and marketing communications, and to detect, prevent, mitigate and investigate fraudulent or illegal activity. We also share your information with third parties for these purposes.

### Learn more

Below you will find a summary of the purposes for which we process your personal data, including the categories of recipients to whom we transmit personal data for the purposes stated, sorted by legal basis:

### 5.1 We process your personal data in order to fulfil our contract with you and to provide you with our Services. This includes the following purposes:

  * Processing of data relating to you or your company for the purpose of entering into a contract with you and executing it.
  * Provision of our Services, including but not limited to: enabling and performing transactions with other users (including the transmission of your personal data to other users where necessary to perform the transaction, including in cases of terminated, failed or subsequently voided transactions), providing and enhancing features such as payment processing, ratings and eBay account management, providing other services you may use (as described in connection with such services), and ensuring the functionality of our Services. In connection with the provision of our Services, we will send you notifications relating to the execution of transactions and the use of our Services in accordance with the communication preferences in your eBay account.
  * Enabling the delivery of purchased items by logistics/shipping service providers including notifications in connection with the delivery (such as tracking information), the latter to the extent permitted by applicable law without your consent.
  * Provision of our payment services.
  * Solution of problems with your eBay account, arbitration of disputes, providing other services within the scope of customer service as well as enforcement of fee claims. For these purposes, we may contact you via notification in My eBay, email, telephone, SMS, push notification on your mobile device or by mail. If we contact you by telephone, in order to ensure efficiency, we may use automatically dialled calls with tape announcements or automated text messages in accordance with our User Agreement and Payments Services Agreement, to the extent permitted by applicable law.
  * Processing of general location data (such as IP address or postcode) in order to provide you with location-based services (such as radius search and other content that is personalised on the basis of your general location data).
  * Enforcement of our User Agreement, the Payments Services Agreement, this User Privacy Notice and other rules and policies.
  * Publication and promotion of your listings and related content on the websites or in the applications, services and tools of other eBay Inc. corporate family members or cooperating third-party operators of websites, applications, services and tools. When we share the content of your listings and any related personal data with third parties, we do so only on the basis of an agreement that limits the use of such personal data by the third party to the purposes necessary to fulfil its contractual obligations to us. Third-party providers are contractually obliged to take appropriate security measures with regard to this data. Third-party providers are strictly forbidden to pass on personal data contained in your listings to other third parties. In case of data transmissions to eBay Inc. corporate family members, such restrictions result from our Binding Corporate Rules (see section **6.1 Data transfers to eBay Inc. corporate family members** under section 6\. International data transfers below).

**Where necessary, we transmit your personal data to processors and the following recipients for one or several of the purposes described above:**

  * Other eBay users
  * [eBay Inc. corporate family members \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/our-businesses/)
  * External service providers and shipping companies (such as DHL, UPS etc.)
  * Payment service providers, including the PayPal Inc. group of companies
  * External operators of websites, applications, services and tools.

### 5.2 We process your personal data in order to comply with legal obligations to which we are subject. This includes the following purposes:

  * Participation in proceedings (including judicial proceedings) conducted by public authorities or government agencies, in particular, for the purpose of detecting, investigating and prosecuting illegal acts.
  * Prevention, detection and mitigation of illegal activities (e.g. fraud, money laundering and terrorist financing).
  * Ensuring the information security of our Services.
  * Retention and storage of your personal data to comply with specific legal retention requirements (for more information on eBay's storage of your data, see section 7\. Storage duration and erasure below).

**Where necessary, we transmit your personal data to processors and the following recipients for one or several of the purposes described above:**

  * Law enforcement agencies, courts, government agencies or public authorities, intergovernmental or supranational bodies (in connection with our payment services provided in the EU for sellers in particular with regard to compliance with Luxembourg laws concerning FATCA dated 7 July 2015 and concerning the OECD Common Reporting Standard dated 18 December 2015).
  * Third-party service providers
  * Third parties who are involved in judicial proceedings, in particular, if they submit a legal order, court order or equivalent legal order to us.
  * Third-party service providers to assist us with the prevention, detection, mitigation, and investigation of potentially illegal acts, money laundering and terrorist financing.
  * Credit agencies bureaus or associations, if required by applicable law (e.g. information on payment delays, payment defaults or other irregularities that may be relevant to your credit report).
  * [eBay Inc. corporate family members \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/our-businesses/)

### 5.3 We process your personal data in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. This includes the following purposes:

  * Prevention, detection, mitigation and investigation of unlawful activities that may result in impairment of your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person, unless there is a statutory obligation to this effect.

**Where necessary, we transmit your personal data to processors and the following recipients for one or several of the purposes described above:**

  * Law enforcement agencies, courts, government agencies or public authorities, intergovernmental or supranational bodies
  * Third parties who are involved in judicial proceedings
  * [eBay Inc. corporate family members \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/our-businesses/)
  * External service providers.

### 5.4 We process your personal data where necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In order to reconcile our legitimate interests with your rights, we have introduced appropriate control mechanisms. On this basis, we process your data for the following purposes:

  * Participation in proceedings (including judicial proceedings) conducted by courts, law enforcement agencies, government agencies or public authorities, intergovernmental or supranational bodies, in particular for the purpose of detecting, investigating and prosecuting illegal acts, unless there is a statutory obligation to this effect, and we may legitimately assume that the disclosure of the data is necessary to avert imminent disadvantages or to report a suspicion of an illegal act. In such cases, we will only disclose what we believe is necessary, such as your name, city, postcode, telephone number, email address, (previous) usernames, IP address, fraud complaints, bidding and listing history.
  * Protection of the legitimate interests of third parties in connection with civil law disputes, unless there is a statutory obligation to this effect, if we may legitimately assume that it is necessary to disclose the data to such third parties in order to avert imminent disadvantages.
  * Prevention, detection, mitigation and investigation of fraud, security breaches and other prohibited or unlawful activities, including the assessment of corresponding risks (e.g. through the use of captchas or the telephone number stored in your eBay account for two-factor authentication), unless there is a statutory obligation to this effect.
  * Monitoring and improvement of the information security of our Services, unless there is a statutory obligation to this effect.
  * Performance of identity checks, creditworthiness and other financial standing checks, evaluation of applications and comparison of information for accuracy and verification purposes.
  * Automatic filtering and, where necessary, manual review of messages sent through our messaging tools to prevent fraudulent or suspicious activity or violations of our User Agreement or other rules and policies, including enforcing the prohibition of purchases and sales outside of eBay, as further explained below under **Filtering of messages sent via our messaging tools** (see section 11\. Other important information regarding data protection).
  * Provision of functions for users that make the processing of transactions easier or more convenient (e.g. administration of several delivery addresses).
  * Analysis and improvement of the Services from eBay Inc. corporate family members, e.g. by reviewing information from users about blocked or crashed pages in order to identify and solve problems and to provide you with an improved user experience, including as part of product development.
  * Analysis of telephone conversations with our customer service that we recorded with your consent.
  * Advertisements by mail (according to your communication preferences in your eBay account).
  * To the extent permitted by applicable law without your consent, communications with you via electronic mail (e.g. email) or telephone to offer you vouchers, discounts and special offers, to conduct opinion polls and surveys, and to inform you about our Services (according to your [communication preferences \- opens in new window or tab](https://my.ebay.com.au/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?MyEbay&CurrentPage=MyeBayNotificationPreferences) in your eBay account). If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us, you can also unsubscribe by clicking on the link in the email you received. For technical reasons, the implementation may take a few days.
  * Notifications regarding promotions and information about our Services after logging into your account or in [Messages \- opens in new window or tab](https://mesg.ebay.com.au/mesgweb/ViewMessages/0) in My eBay (according to your [communication preferences \- opens in new window or tab](https://my.ebay.com.au/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?MyEbay&CurrentPage=MyeBayNotificationPreferences) in your eBay account).
  * For users outside the European Economic Area (EEA): Personalisation, measurement and improvement of our and third-party advertisements in our online offerings, the online offerings of other eBay Inc. corporate family members or third parties.
  * Customisation of page content to display the items and services you may like based on the actions you take.
  * Evaluation of the quality and success of our email marketing campaigns (e.g. through analysis of opening and click rates).
  * Assessment of the service status (e.g. on the basis of tracking information if sellers use postage labels from delivery providers via eBay or provide tracking numbers).
  * Offering of partner and bonus programs, co-branding credit cards.
  * Provision of shared content and services (such as registration for services, transaction processing and customer service) with eBay Inc. corporate family members or cooperating payment service providers.
  * Initiation, preparation and execution of a company acquisition, e.g. in the event of a merger with another company or takeover by another company. If such an event occurs, we will require the merged entity to comply with this User Privacy Notice with respect to your personal data. Should your personal data be processed for any purpose not specified in this User Privacy Notice, you will be informed in advance of the processing of your data for this new purpose.
  * Assertion of or defence against legal claims, including those asserted by one eBay user against another eBay user.

**Where necessary, we transmit your personal data to processors and the following recipients for one or several of the purposes described above:**

  * [eBay Inc. corporate family members \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/our-businesses/)
  * External service providers
  * Other eBay users
  * Law enforcement agencies, courts, government agencies or public authorities, intergovernmental or supranational bodies
  * Third parties who are involved in judicial proceedings
  * Payment service providers, including the PayPal Inc. group of companies
  * Credit agencies or bureaus (e.g. information about payment delays, payment defaults or other irregularities that may be relevant to your credit report)
  * Other companies in the context of a company acquisition
  * Participants in the eBay VeRO program in the event of an investigation for fraud, intellectual property infringement, product piracy or other unlawful activity, if we, in our sole discretion, deem the investigation of such incident necessary or useful. In such cases, we will disclose the seller's name, address, city, postcode, country, telephone number, email address and company name to the participant of the eBay VeRO program and bind the participant by a worldwide non-disclosure agreement to treat the data as confidential.

Information about your right to object to processing based on our legitimate interests can be found below under section 8\. Rights as a data subject and, with regard to the use of cookies and similar technologies, below under section 9\. Cookies & similar technologies.

### 5.5 With your consent, we process your personal data for the following purposes:

  * For users within the European Economic Area (EEA): Personalisation, measurement and improvement of our and third-party advertisements in our online offerings, the online offerings of other eBay Inc. corporate family members or third parties.
  * Marketing communications by telephone or electronic mail (such as email or SMS), including communications by other eBay Inc. corporate family members or by third parties, unless these communications are permitted without your consent under applicable law.
  * Processing of your exact location data to provide location-based services.
  * Processing of your personal data on the basis of your consent, which you have given so that we or third parties can enable you to use certain services or make them available to you.

You can find information about your right to withdraw your consent below under section 8\. Rights as a data subject and information with regard to the use of cookies and similar technologies below under section 9\. Cookies & similar technologies.

**Where necessary, we transmit your personal data to processors and the following recipients for one or several of the purposes described above:**

  * [eBay Inc. corporate family members \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/our-businesses/)
  * External service providers
  * Other third parties with whom we partner to offer you specific services (as described at the collection of the respective user consent)
  * Third-party financial institutions with whom we partner to offer financial products to you, for them to provide joint content and services (such as registration, transactions and customer support). These third-party financial institution partners will use your personal data to send you marketing communications only if you have requested their services

Without your consent, we will not pass on your personal data to third parties for their marketing or advertising purposes, nor will we sell or otherwise make it available to third parties for a fee.

### 5.6 Data Sharing between eBay Inc. Corporate Family Members

As set out above under "Personal data from other sources", we also receive access to personal data about you from other [eBay Inc. corporate family members \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/our-businesses/). This enables us, in particular, to provide you, with your consent as legally required, with information about products and services, which we believe might interest you, and improve our products, services, content, and advertising by analysing your use of the services of other eBay Inc. corporate family members, in particular through the matching of certain data (e.g. cookie IDs). Furthermore, this allows us to better prevent, detect, mitigate and investigate fraud, security breaches and other prohibited or unlawful activities, including the assessment of corresponding risks. We will also grant access to personal data about you to other eBay Inc. corporate family members for the aforementioned purposes. To the extent that other eBay Inc. corporate family members have access to your personal data, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this User Privacy Notice.

### 5.7 Additional information regarding our payment services for sellers

With regard to our payment services for sellers in the EU, we additionally point out that eBay S.à r.l. is subject to professional secrecy, which requires special transparency with regard to the processing and, in particular, the transmission of your personal data. We therefore expressly draw your attention to the fact that eBay S.à r.l. may pass on your personal data to trustworthy third parties and business partners where necessary to provide our payment services for sellers, as described above in this Section 5 of the User Privacy Notice. This includes in particular the following third parties and business partners:

  * Other payment service providers, including financial institutions
  * Companies offering financial products, analyses and scoring (e.g. credit agencies or bureaus)
  * Authorities, agencies and other governmental bodies (e.g. to combat fraud)
  * Auditors and other professional advisors.

You can request a complete list of all third party providers and business partners for our payment services for sellers in the EU by contacting us.

### 5.8 Automated decision-making

We use technologies that are considered automated decision making or profiling. We will not make any automated decisions about you that would significantly affect you unless such a decision is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract with you, we have obtained your consent, or we are required by applicable law to use such technology. You will find information on your right to object to this processing of your data below under section 8\. Rights as a data subject.

### 5.9 Main consequences if you do not provide your personal data to us

If you do not provide us with the information we request or if we cannot collect this information from other sources, we may not be able to provide you with our services.

## 6\. International data transfers

Some recipients of your personal data are located outside your country or have offices in countries where data protection laws may provide a different level of protection than the laws in your country. When transferring personal data to such recipients, we provide appropriate safeguards.

### Learn more

### 6.1 Data transfers to eBay Inc. corporate family members

The transmission of personal data between different eBay Inc. corporate family members is based on our worldwide data protection principles, which are binding internal data protection regulations (Binding Corporate Rules, BCRs), or on the basis of other appropriate safeguards (e.g. standard data protection clauses issued or approved by the European Commission (2010/87/EU, 2001/497/EC or 2004/915/EC)). Through our Binding Corporate Rules, the eBay Inc. corporate family members undertake to protect your personal data and to comply with data protection obligations. Further information on our binding company-wide guidelines and our worldwide data protection principles can be found in the [eBay Privacy Center \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/).

### 6.2 Other data transfers (from the European Economic Area to third countries)

We will only transfer your personal data from the European Economic Area (EEA) to third countries, i.e. countries outside the EEA, on the basis of appropriate safeguards. Third countries providing an adequate level of data protection according to the European Commission currently include Andorra, Argentina, Canada (for companies covered by the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act), Switzerland, the Faroe Islands, Guernsey, the State of Israel, the Isle of Man, Japan, Jersey, New Zealand and Uruguay. Recipients in the USA can be partially certified according to the [EU-U.S. Privacy Shield \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome), so that appropriate safeguards for an international data transfer exist. In other cases, eBay provides the necessary safeguards, e.g. through the conclusion of data protection contracts adopted by the European Commission (e.g. standard data protection clauses (2010/87/EU, 2001/497/EC or 2004/915/EC)) with the recipients, or through other measures provided for by law. A copy of the documentation of the measures taken by us is available on request.

## 7\. Storage duration and erasure

Your personal data will be stored by us and our service providers in accordance with applicable data protection laws to the extent necessary for the processing purposes set out in this User Privacy Notice (see section 5\. Purposes and legal basis for data processing and categories of recipients for more information on the processing purposes). Subsequently, we will delete your personal data in accordance with our data retention and deletion policy or take steps to properly render the data anonymous, unless we are legally obliged to keep your personal data longer (e.g. for tax, accounting or auditing purposes). In Europe, the retention periods are generally between 6 and 10 years (e.g. for contracts, notifications and business letters). As far as legally permissible or required, we restrict the processing of your data instead of deleting it (e.g. by restricting access to it). This applies in particular to cases where we may still need the data for the execution of the contract or for the assertion of or defence against legal claims. In these cases, the duration of the restriction of processing depends on the respective statutory limitation or retention periods. The data will be deleted after the relevant limitation or retention periods have expired.

### Learn more

The specific retention periods for personal data are documented in our regional data retention guidelines. How long we retain personal data may vary depending on the Services we provide and our legal obligations under applicable national law. The following factors typically affect the retention period:

  * **Necessity for the provision of our Services**  
This includes such things as executing the User Agreement with you, maintaining and improving the performance of our products, keeping our systems secure, and maintaining appropriate business and financial records. Most of our retention periods are determined on the basis of this general rule.
  * **Special categories of personal data**  
If we store special categories of personal data, a shorter retention period is usually appropriate.
  * **Consent-based processing of personal data**  
If we process personal data on the basis of consent (including consent to the extended storage), we store the data for as long as necessary in order to process it according to your consent.
  * **Statutory, contractual or other similar obligations**  
Corresponding storage obligations may arise, for example, from laws or official orders. It may also be necessary to store personal data with regard to pending or future legal disputes. Personal data contained in contracts, notifications and business letters may be subject to statutory storage obligations depending on national law.

## 8\. Rights as a data subject

Subject to possible restrictions under national law, as a data subject, you have the right to access, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing and data portability with regard to your personal data. In addition, you can withdraw your consent and **object** to our processing of your personal data on the basis of legitimate interests. You can also lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

### Learn more

Your rights in detail:

  * You can **withdraw your consent** to the processing of your personal data by us at any time. As a result, we may no longer process your personal data based on this consent in the future. The withdrawal of consent has no effect on the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.
  * You have the right to obtain **access** to your personal data that is being processed by us. In particular, you may request information on the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned, the categories of recipients to whom the personal data have been or will be disclosed, the envisaged period for which the personal data will be stored, the existence of the right to request rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing of personal data or to object to such processing, the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, any available information as to the personal data's source (where they are not collected from you), the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling and, where appropriate, meaningful information on its details. Your right to access may be limited by national law.
  * You have the right to obtain from us without undue delay the **rectification** of inaccurate personal data concerning you. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.
  * You have the right to obtain from us the **erasure** of personal data concerning you, unless processing is necessary for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information, for compliance with a legal obligation, for reasons of public interest or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. The right to erasure may be limited by national law.
  * You have the right to obtain from us **restriction of processing** to the extent that 
    * the accuracy of the data is disputed by you,
    * the processing is unlawful, but you oppose the erasure of the personal data,
    * we no longer need the data, but you need it to assert, exercise or defend legal claims or
    * you have objected to the processing.
  * You have the right to receive the personal data concerning you, which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit those data to another controller (" **right to data portability** ").
  * You have the right to lodge a complaint with a **supervisory authority**. As a rule, you can contact the supervisory authority of your usual place of residence, your place of work or the registered office of the controller.

If your personal data is processed on the basis of legitimate interests, you have the **right to object** to the processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation. This also applies to profiling. If your personal data is processed by us for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of your personal data for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.

The exercise of the above data subjects' rights (e.g. right to access or erasure) is generally free of charge. Where requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive, in particular because of their repetitive character, we may charge an appropriate fee (at most our actual costs) in accordance with the applicable statutory regulations or refuse to process the application.

### Exercising your rights and managing your settings

You can exercise your rights as a data subject via our [contact forms \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/privacy-contact/). In addition, you are of course free to contact us in any other way.

If you would like to change your preferences regarding eBay notifications (including marketing communications), you can do so at any time in My eBay under [Communication preferences \- opens in new window or tab](https://my.ebay.com.au/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?MyEbay&CurrentPage=MyeBayNotificationPreferences). If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us, you can also unsubscribe by clicking on the link in the email you received. For technical reasons, the implementation may take a few days. For information on how to manage your cookie and similar technology preferences, see the next section 9\. Cookies & similar technologies.

## 9\. Cookies & similar technologies

When you use our Services, we and selected third parties may use cookies and similar technologies to provide you with a better, faster and safer user experience or to show you personalised advertising. Cookies are small text files that are automatically created by your browser and stored on your device when you use the Services. You can find detailed information about our use of cookies and similar technologies and your choices in our User Cookie Notice.

### Learn more

Our cookies and similar technologies have different functions:

  * They may be technically necessary for the provision of our Services.
  * They help us optimise our Services technically (e.g. monitoring of error messages and loading times).
  * They help us improve your user experience (e.g. save font size and form data entered).
  * They allow us to show you more relevant advertisements.

We use cookies and similar technologies that remain on your device only as long as your browser is active (session cookies), as well as cookies and similar technologies that remain on your device longer (permanent cookies). Where possible, we take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorised access to our cookies and similar technologies. A unique ID ensures that only we and/or selected third parties have access to cookie data.

### Your choices regarding cookies

You are free to disable the use of cookies and similar technologies if this is supported by your device. You can manage your cookie settings in your browser or device settings. In addition, you can decide whether we may use cookies and similar technologies to show you personalised advertisements:

  * To manage the settings regarding the use of first-party cookies (and similar technologies) for advertising-related purposes, please go to [AdChoice - eBay Advertising Preferences \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebay.com/adchoice) (you can also access this page directly via a link in the respective advertisement or the footer of our website)
  * You can find information about third-party cookies (and similar technologies) related to advertising and how to prevent their use on the following websites: 
    * [www.networkadvertising.org/choices \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices)
  * Users in the European Economic Area (EEA) can also use [Advertising and related preferences \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebay.com/gdpr) to determine to what extent they consent to the processing of their personal data for advertising purposes via cookies (and similar technologies)

If you decide not to have your personal data processed by us for advertising purposes via cookies (and similar technologies), this does not mean that we will not show you advertisements. It simply means that these advertisements will not be personalised for you using first-party or third-party cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies.

## 10\. Data security

We protect your personal data through technical and organisational security measures to minimise risks associated with data loss, misuse, unauthorised access and unauthorised disclosure and alteration. To this end we use firewalls and data encryption, for example, as well as physical access restrictions for our data centres and authorisation controls for data access. You can find further information on data security in our [Security Center \- opens in new window or tab](https://pages.ebay.com/securitycenter/index.html).

## 11\. Other important information regarding data protection

This section contains important additional information about the protection of personal data in connection with the use of our Services, including whether you are required to provide personal data.

### Learn more

### What happens when you share your personal data on our sites or applications?

Other users have access to the information you share on eBay or disclose to other users. For example, other users can see your bids, purchases, items for sale, saved interests, sellers and searches, storefronts, Feedback, ratings, product reviews and associated comments. Other users can also see any information you chose to share in your profile.

When you use our Services, your public username may be displayed and available to the public and associated with all of your public eBay activity. Notices sent to other users about suspicious activity and notice violations on our sites may refer to your public username and specific items. Accordingly, if you use a username that allows others to identify you, these others may be able to identify your eBay activities.

To help protect your personal data, we allow only limited access to other users' contact, delivery and financial information as necessary to facilitate your transactions and collect payments. However, when users are involved in a transaction, they have access to each other's name, username, email address and other contact and delivery information.

### Your responsibilities over transactional information you receive through eBay

When you complete a transaction with another user (or a transaction has been cancelled, failed, or subsequently invalidated), we will provide you with the other user's personal data (such as name, username, email address, contact information, delivery and billing information). Independent from us, you are the controller of such data and responsible for any processing.

Unless you act for purely personal purposes, we recommend that you explain your data processing activities in your own privacy notice and protect the privacy of other users. As a seller, you must in any case comply with the applicable data protection laws and in particular protect the rights of other users as data subjects, e.g. give them the opportunity to access the personal data collected by you and demand that it be erased.

You may use the personal data that you have access to only for eBay transaction-related purposes, or for other Services offered through eBay (such as delivery, fraud complaints and member-to-member communications), and for purposes expressly consented by the user to whom the data relates. Using personal data of other users that you have access to for any other purpose constitutes a violation of our User Agreement.

### Personal data relating to third parties

If you provide us with personal data relating to another person, you must obtain the consent of this person or the disclosure of the data to us must be otherwise legally permissible. You must inform the other person of how we process personal data in accordance with our User Privacy Notice.

### Filtering of messages sent via our messaging tools

We filter the messages sent via our messaging tools automatically according to certain criteria and check conspicuous messages manually if necessary. The messages are first received by us and then forwarded to the recipient. All messages are automatically filtered according to certain criteria. If necessary, conspicuous messages are checked manually by our customer service. In the event of a violation, we reserve the right to block the transmission of the message and to restrict the purchase and sales functions of your eBay account or to block your eBay account.

This is to protect legitimate interests such as protecting against fraudulent or suspicious activities (e.g. spam, viruses, phishing or other illegal activities) or enforcing our User Agreement and our other rules and policies (e.g. illegal and other prohibited content), including but not limited to enforcing the prohibition of purchases and sales outside of eBay.

### Are you obliged to provide your personal data to us?

Some of the personal data that you provide to us (e.g. data by which we can identify you) are required to enter into the User Agreement and the Payments Services Agreement. The provision of any other personal data is voluntary, but may be necessary for the use of our Services, such as bidding, purchase and sales data to complete a transaction.

### Children's Privacy

Our services are not intended for the use by children. We do not knowingly collect personal data from users who are considered children under applicable national laws. According to our User Agreement, children are not permitted to use our Services.

### Staying Signed in

When you sign in to your account on our Services, we give you the option to stay signed in to your account for certain amount of time. If you are using a public or shared computer, we encourage you not to choose to stay signed in. You or any other user of the computer/browser you signed in on will be able to view and access most parts of your account and take certain specific actions during this signed-in period without any further authorisation. The specific actions and account activities that you or any other user of this computer/browser may take include:

  * Bid, buy or make an offer on an item
  * Check out or add items to your cart
  * Purchase an item with PayPal using Faster Checkout (if enabled in your account)
  * View the activity header
  * View the My eBay page
  * View or edit the Watchlist or order details
  * View the profile page
  * Send member-to-member messages
  * Conduct after-sale activities, like leaving Feedback, cancelling orders, requesting returns or submitting claims.

If you attempt to change your password or username, update any other account information or attempt other account activity beyond those listed above, you may be required to enter your password.

You can typically end your signed-in session by either signing out and/or clearing your cookies. If you have certain browser privacy settings enabled, simply closing your browser may also end your signed-in session. If you are using a public or shared computer, you should sign out and/or clear your cookies when you are done using our Services to protect your account and your personal data.

## Previous privacy policy

### Previous privacy policy (posted on 1 May 2018 and effective for existing users until 29 July 2019)

eBay is committed to your privacy. This privacy notice explains our collection, use, disclosure, retention, and protection of your personal information.

## Scope

This privacy notice applies to any eBay website, application, service, or tool (collectively "Services") where this privacy notice is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them, including through mobile devices.

### Learn more: Scope

This privacy notice applies to any eBay website, application, service, or tool (collectively "Services") where this privacy notice is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them, including through mobile devices.

This privacy notice also applies to the provision of eBay services through any eBay partner's website, application, service, or tool where it is referenced and where your listings and their content are published or advertised in accordance with the terms of this privacy notice.

We may amend this privacy notice at any time by posting the amended version on this site including the effective date of the amended version. We will announce any material changes to this privacy notice through the eBay Message Centre and/or via email.

## Personal information we collect

**What is personal information?**

Personal Information is information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier, or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

We do not consider personal information to include information that has been anonymised or aggregated so that it can no longer be used to identify a specific natural person, whether in combination with other information or otherwise.

We collect personal information from you and other sources when you use our Services.

If you do not provide us with the information we request or if we cannot collect this information from other sources, we may not be able to provide you with our services.

### Learn more: Personal information we collect

We collect personal information from you and any devices (including mobile devices) you use when you: use our Services, register for an account with us, provide us information on a web form, update or add information to your account, participate in a community board discussion chat, or when you otherwise correspond with us.

Some of this personal information, such as a way to identify you, is necessary to enter into our User Agreement. The provision of all other personal information is voluntary, but may be necessary in order to use our Services, such as the bidding, buying or selling information needed to conclude a transaction.

We may also collect personal information from other sources, as described below.

### Personal information you give us when you use our Services or register for an account with us

  * Identifying information such as your name, addresses, telephone numbers or email addresses when you register for an account with us
  * Bidding, buying, or selling information you provide during a transaction, or other transaction-based content that you generate or that is connected to your account as a result of a transaction you are involved in
  * Other content that you generate, or that is connected to your account (such as adding items to your cart, adding items to your Watch List, creating collections, and following other collections and sellers)
  * Financial information (such as credit card or bank account numbers) in connection with a transaction
  * Postage, billing and other information used to purchase or send an item, as well as, where postal services are provided through one of our programs, information required to clear customs (such as Tax ID or other identification numbers) and relevant postage information (such as tracking numbers and tracking updates)
  * In some instances, when you use our Services, you may provide age, gender, interests and favourites
  * You may also provide us other information through a web form, by updating or adding information to your account, through your participation in community discussions, member-to-member communications, chats, dispute resolution, or when you otherwise communicate with us regarding our Services
  * Additional information we are required or authorised by applicable national laws to collect and process in order to authenticate or identify you or to verify the information we have collected

### Personal information we collect automatically when you use our Services or register for an account with us

  * We collect information about your interaction with our Services, your advertising preferences, and your communications with us. This is information we receive from devices (including mobile devices) you use when you access our Services. This information could include the following: Device ID or unique identifier, device type, ID for advertising, and unique device token
  * Location information, including location information from your mobile device. Keep in mind that most mobile devices allow you to control or disable the use of location services by any application on your mobile device in the device's settings menu
  * Computer and connection information such as statistics on your page views, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, your IP address, your browsing history, and your web log information

### Personal information we collect using cookies and similar technologies

  * We use cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers, and similar technologies to collect information about the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions you take when using our Services, within our advertising or email content
  * For more information about our use of these technologies, and how to control them, see Cookies and Similar Technologies

### Personal information collected from other sources

  * We supplement the personal information we collect directly with information collected from third parties and add it to your account information. For example, we collect and use demographic and other information that is publically available in an applicable jurisdiction, additional contact information, credit check information, and information from credit bureaus, as allowed by applicable national laws
  * **Social Media:** We allow you to share information with social media sites, or use social media sites to create your account or to connect your account with the respective social media site. Those social media sites may give us automatic access to certain personal information retained by them about you (e.g., content viewed by you, content liked by you, and information about the advertisements you have been shown or have clicked on, etc.). If you provide us with access to any site with video content, then you agree that we can share your video viewing with, or obtain information about your video viewing from, third-party social media sites for at least two years or until you withdraw authorisation or connection to the social media site. You control the personal information you allow us to have access to through the privacy settings on the applicable social media site and the permissions you give us when you grant us access to the personal information retained by the respective social media site about you. By associating an account managed by a social media site with your account and authorising us to have access to this information, you agree that we can collect, use and retain the information provided by these social media sites in accordance with this privacy notice. We may also use plug-ins or other technologies from various social media sites. If you click on a link provided via a social media plug in, you are voluntarily establishing a connection with that respective social media site
  * If you give us personal information about someone else, you must do so only with that person's authorisation. You should inform them how we collect, use, disclose, and retain their personal information according to our privacy notice

## How we use your personal information

We use your personal information to provide and improve our Services, provide you with a personalised experience on our sites, contact you about your account and our Services, provide you customer service, provide you with personalised advertising and marketing, and to detect, prevent, mitigate and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities.

### Learn more: How we use your personal information

We use the personal information we collect from you for a range of different business purposes and according to different legal bases of processing. The following is a summary of how and according to which legal bases we use your personal information.

**We use your personal information to fulfil a contract with you and provide you with our Services, to comply with our legal obligation, protect your vital interest, or as may be required for the public good. This includes:**

  * To provide payment processing and account management, operate, measure and improve our Services, keep our Services safe, secure and operational, and customise site content that includes items and services that you may like in response to actions that you take
  * To contact you regarding your account, to troubleshoot problems with your account, to resolve a dispute, to collect fees or monies owed or as otherwise necessary to provide you customer service 
    * When contacting you for such purposes as outlined above, we may contact you via email, telephone, SMS/text messages, postal mail, and via mobile push notifications
    * When contacting you via telephone, to ensure efficiency, we may use autodialled or pre-recorded calls and text messages as described in our User Agreement and as authorised by applicable law. Message and data rates may apply
  * To provide other services requested by you as described when we collect the information
  * We use general location information to provide you with location based services (such as advertising, search results, and other personalised content)
  * To prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate fraud, security breaches or other potentially prohibited or illegal activities
  * To enforce our User Agreement, this privacy notice, or other policies, and to monitor restrictions on offers to buy or sell outside of eBay and member-to-member communications for violations of our policies or applicable laws

**We use your personal information to pursue our legitimate interests where your rights and freedoms do not outweigh these interests. We have implemented controls to balance our interests with your rights. This includes to:**

  * Improve our Services, for example by reviewing information associated with stalled or crashed pages experienced by users allowing us to identify and fix problems and give you a better experience
  * Personalise, measure, and improve our advertising based on your advertising customisation preferences
  * Contact you via email or postal mail in order to offer you vouchers, coupons, discounts and special promotions, poll your opinions through surveys or questionnaires and inform you about our Services, as authorised by applicable law
  * Contact you about public policy matters, or other current events, related to your ability to use our Services. This could include an invitation to join a petition, letter writing, call or other sort of public policy related campaigns
  * Deliver targeted marketing, service updates, and promotional offers based on your communication preferences
  * Measure the performance of our email marketing campaigns (e.g. by analysing open and click rates)
  * Measure sellers' performance (e.g. by using shipment tracking information that sellers and shipping providers send or provide through eBay)
  * Monitor and improve the information security of our site and mobile applications

**With your consent, we may use your personal information to:**

  * Provide you with marketing via telephone calls, SMS or text
  * Provide you with marketing from other eBay Inc. corporate family members
  * Provide you with marketing from third parties
  * Customise third party advertising you might see on third party websites
  * Use your precise geo-location to provide location based services
  * Use your sensitive personal information to facilitate transactions in certain categories

You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.

We may use technologies considered automated decision making or profiling. We will not make automated-decisions about you that would significantly affect you, unless such a decision is necessary as part of a contract we have with you, we have your consent, or we are required by law to use such technology.

## Your choices about how we use your personal information

You have choices about how we use your personal information to communicate with you, to send you marketing information, how we provide you with customised and relevant advertising, and whether you want to stay signed into your account.

### Learn more: Your choices about how we use your personal information

### Communication preferences

### Communication preferences

You can control your email communication preferences in the Communication Preference section within your My eBay. There, you can also control your member-to-member communications preferences setting and choose which newsletters and promotions you want to receive.

### Marketing

If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us, you can unsubscribe via the link in an email you received, change your Communication Preferences within My eBay, indicate your communication preferences using the method described within the direct communication from us or contact us as described in the Contact Us section below. Keep in mind, we do not sell, rent, or otherwise disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your consent.

### Advertising

If you do not wish to participate in our advertising personalisation programs, you can opt out by following the directions provided within the applicable advertisement, or through the programs described in our User Cookie Notice. The effect of an opt-out will be to stop personalised advertising, but it will still allow the collection of personal information as otherwise described in this privacy notice. We do not allow third parties to track or collect your personal information on our sites for their own advertising purposes, without your consent.

### Staying Signed in

When you sign in to your account on our Services, we give you the option to stay signed in to your account for certain amount of time. If you are using a public or shared computer, we encourage you not to choose to stay signed in. You or any other user of the computer/browser you signed in on will be able to view and access most parts of your account and take certain specific actions during this signed in period without any further authorisation. The specific actions and account activities that you or any other user of this computer/browser may take include:

  * Bid, buy or make an offer on an item
  * Check out or add items to your cart
  * Purchase an item with PayPal using Faster Checkout (if enabled in your account)
  * View the activity header
  * View the My eBay page
  * View or edit the Watch List or order details
  * View the profile page
  * Send member-to-member messages
  * Conduct after-sale activities, like leaving Feedback, cancelling orders, requesting returns or submitting claims

If you attempt to change your password, username, update any other account information or attempt other account activity beyond those listed above, you may be required to enter your password.

You can typically end your signed in session by either signing out and/or clearing your cookies. If you have certain browser privacy settings enabled, simply closing your browser may also end your signed in session. If you are using a public or shared computer, you should sign out and/or clear your cookies when you are done using our Services to protect your account and your personal information.

## Ways you can access, control, and correct your personal information

We respect your right to access, correct, request deletion or request restriction of our usage of your personal information as required by applicable law. We also take steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date.

  * You have the right to know what personal information we maintain about you
  * We will provide you with a copy of your personal information in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format on request
  * If your personal information is incorrect or incomplete, you have the right to ask us to update it
  * You have the right to object to our processing of your personal information
  * You can also ask us to delete or restrict how we use your personal information, but this right is determined by applicable law and may impact your access to some of our Services

### Learn more: Ways you can access, control, and correct your personal information

### Access, correction, and deletion of your personal information

You can see, review and change most of your personal information by signing in to your account. Please, update your personal information immediately if it changes or is inaccurate. Keep in mind, once you make a public posting, you may not be able to change or remove it.

We will honour any statutory right you might have to access, modify or erase your personal information. To request access and to find out whether any fees may apply, if permitted by applicable national laws, please contact us following the instructions in the Contact Us section below. Where you have a statutory right to request access or request the modification or erasure of your personal information, we can still withhold that access or decline to modify or erase your personal information in some cases in accordance with applicable national laws.

If you request that we stop processing some or all of your personal information or you withdraw (where applicable) your consent for our use or disclosure of your personal information for purposes set out in this privacy notice, we might not be able to provide you all of the Services and customer support offered to our users and authorised under this privacy notice and our User Agreement.

Upon your request, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable national laws.

## How we might share your personal information

We may disclose your personal information to other members of the eBay Inc. corporate family or to third parties. This disclosure may be required for us to provide you access to our Services, to comply with our legal obligations, to enforce our User Agreement, to facilitate our marketing and advertising activities, or to prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities related to our Services. We attempt to minimise the amount of personal information we disclose to what is directly relevant and necessary to accomplish the specified purpose. We do not sell, rent, or otherwise disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing and advertising purposes without your consent.

### Learn more: How we might share your personal information

We may disclose your personal information to the following parties for the following purposes:

### eBay Inc. corporate family members globally, who may use it to:

  * Provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions, and customer support)
  * Help detect, investigate, mitigate and prevent potentially fraudulent and illegal acts, violations of our User Agreement, and data security breaches
  * Provide you personalised advertising
  * Improve their products, sites, applications, services, tools, and marketing communications
  * Members of our eBay Inc. corporate family will use your personal information to send you marketing communications only if you have consented to receive such communications from them or if otherwise permitted by the law

### Service Providers and financial institutions partners as follows:

  * Third party service providers who help us to provide our Services, payment processing services, assist us in providing customise advertising, to assist us with the prevention, detection, mitigation, and investigation of potentially illegal acts, violations of our User Agreement, fraud and/or security breaches, bill collection, affiliate and rewards programs, co-branded credit cards and other business operations
  * Third party financial institutions with whom we partner to offer financial products to you, for them to provide joint content and services (such as, registration, transactions and customer support). These third party financial institution partners will use your personal information to send you marketing communications only if you have requested their services
  * Third party shipping providers (e.g., DHL, UPS, USPS, etc.) with whom we share delivery address, contact information and shipment tracking information for the purposes of facilitating the delivery of items purchased and other delivery related communications
  * Third party providers of websites, applications, services and tools that we cooperate with so that they can publish or advertise your listings and their content on their websites or in their applications, services and tools. If we transfer personal information along with the content of your listings to third party providers, this will be solely on the basis of an agreement limiting use by the third party provider of such personal information to processing necessary to fulfil their contract with us and obligating the third party provider to take security measures with regard to such data. Third party providers are not permitted to sell, lease or in any other way transfer the personal information included in your listings to third parties

### Law enforcement, legal proceedings, and as authorised by law

  * To comply with our legal requirements, enforce our User Agreement, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect anyone's rights, property or safety
  * To law enforcement or governmental agencies, or authorised third-parties, in response to a verified request or legal process relating to a criminal investigation or alleged or suspected illegal activity or any other activity that exposes us, you, or any other of our users to legal liability. We will only disclose information we deem relevant to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, city, state, postcode, telephone number, email address, username history, IP address, fraud complaints, bidding and listing history
  * To participants of the eBay VeRO Program globally under confidentiality agreement, as we in our sole discretion deem necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. In such events, we will disclose seller's name, street address, city, state, postcode, country, phone number, email address and company name to the participants of the eBay VeRO Program
  * To credit agencies or bureaus as authorised by applicable national laws (e.g. information on late or missed payments or other defaults on your account that may be reflected in your credit report or file)
  * To third parties involved in a legal proceeding, if they provide us with a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal basis, or we otherwise believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity

### Other eBay users as authorised by you or your use of our Services

  * When transacting with another user, the other user may request that we provide him/her with information about you necessary to complete the transaction, such as your name, account ID, email address, contact details, delivery and billing address, or other information from you needed to promote the reliability and security of the transaction
  * If a transaction fails, is put on hold, or is later invalidated, we may also provide the other user with details of the unsuccessful transaction
  * The other user receiving your information should only use it for purposes related to the transaction. Unless you have consented to receive marketing from them, they should not contact you for marketing purposes
  * Contacting users with unwanted or threatening messages is a violation of our User Agreement

### We may disclose your personal information to PayPal Inc. and its corporate family

  * To prevent, detect, mitigate, and investigate potentially illegal acts, fraud and/or security breaches, and to assess and manage risk, including to alert you if fraudulent activities have been detected on your eBay or PayPal accounts
  * To provide customer services, including to help service your account or resolve disputes (e.g., billing or transactional disputes)
  * To facilitate the processing of payment cards when you pay within our Services with a payment card and we use PayPal to process your payment
  * To facilitate delivery and related services for purchases you made using PayPal

### Change of ownership

If we are subject to a merger or acquisition with/by another company, we may share information with them in accordance with our global privacy standards. Should such an event occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this privacy notice with respect to your personal information. If we intend to handle your personal information for any purposes not covered in this privacy notice, you will receive prior notification of the processing of your personal information for the new purposes.

## How long we keep your personal information

We retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide the Services you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our policies.

Our specific retention times for personal information are documented in our regional records retention schedules. How long we retain personal information can vary significantly based on context of the Services we provide and on our legal obligations. The following factors typically influence retention periods:

  * **How long is the personal information needed to provide our Services?** This includes such things as maintaining and improving the performance of our products, keeping our systems secure, and maintaining appropriate business and financial records. This is the general rule that establishes the baseline for most of our data retention periods
  * **Is the personal information sensitive?** If so, a shortened retention time is generally appropriate
  * **Have you provided consent for a longer retention period?** If so, we will retain data in accordance with your consent
  * **Are we subject to a legal, contractual, or similar obligation to retain your personal information?** Examples can include mandatory data retention laws in the applicable jurisdiction, government orders to preserve data relevant to an investigation, or personal information retained for the purposes of litigation

After it is no longer necessary for us to retain your personal information, we will dispose of it in a secure manner according to our data retention and deletion policies.

## Cookies & Similar Technologies

When you visit or interact with our sites, services, applications, tools or messaging, we or our authorised service providers may use cookies and other similar technologies to help provide you with a better, faster, and safer experience, and for advertising and marketing purposes. You can read our full User Cookie Notice for more information.

## How do we protect your personal information

We protect your personal information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorised access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centres, and information access authorisation controls. For more information about staying safe while buying and selling online, or to report an issue with your account please visit our [Security Center \- opens in new window or tab](https://pages.ebay.com/securitycenter/index.html).

## Global Privacy Standards

We have established a set of global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies known as our Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs). They are our commitment to protect your personal information and honour our privacy obligations within our eBay Inc. corporate family. More information about our BCRs and our global privacy standards is available at our [eBay Privacy Center \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/).

## Data Controllers and Data Protection Officers

Learn more about who is your data controller, and is responsible for the collection, use, disclosure, retention and protection of your personal information in accordance with our global privacy standards, this privacy notice, as well as any applicable national laws.

### Learn more: Data Controllers and Data Protection Officers

If you reside in the United States, you are contracting with eBay Inc., 2025 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95125, USA and, if you use our payments services, also with eBay Commerce Inc., 2025 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95125, USA, for such payments services.

If you reside outside of the United States, you are contracting with one of our international eBay companies, as follows:

  * If you reside in Canada, you are contracting with eBay Canada Limited, 500 King Street West, Suite 200, Toronto, ON M5V 1L9, Canada;
  * If you reside in a country within the European Union (except the United Kingdom), you are contracting with eBay GmbH, Albert-Einstein-Ring 2-6, 14532 Kleinmachnow, Germany;
  * If you reside in the United Kingdom, you are contracting with eBay (UK) Limited, 1 More London Place, London, SE1 2AF, United Kingdom;
  * If you reside in India, you are contracting with eBay Singapore Services Pte Ltd, 10 Collyer Quay, #10-01 Ocean Financial Centre, Singapore 049315;
  * If you reside in any other country, you are contracting with eBay Marketplaces GmbH, Helvetiastrasse 15/17, 3005 Bern, Switzerland;
  * If you use our eBay Customer Guarantee services and reside in France, Italy or Spain, you are also contracting with eBay Services S.à r.l, 22-24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg for such specific services.

The company you are contracting with is your data controller, and is responsible for the collection, use, disclosure, retention and protection of your personal information in accordance with our global privacy standards, this privacy notice, as well as any applicable national laws.

Your data controller may transfer data to other members of the eBay Inc. corporate family who have signed our BCRs, as described in this privacy notice.

We may process and retain your personal information on our servers in the U.S. and elsewhere in the world where our data centres are located.

Where we have a legal obligation to do so, we have appointed data protection officers (DPOs) to be responsible for the privacy program at each of the respective data controllers. You can contact any of our DPOs via the Contact Us information detailed below in this privacy notice.

## Other important privacy information

This section describes some additional privacy information related to your use of our Services that you may find important.

### Learn more: Other important privacy information

### When you share your personal information on our sites or applications – what happens?

Other users have access to the information you share on eBay. For example, other users can see your bids, purchases, items for sale, your collections, the sellers and collections you follow, storefronts, feedback, ratings, product reviews and associated comments. Other users can also see any information you chose to share in your profile or your collections.

When you use our Services, your public user ID may be displayed and available to the public and associated with all of your public eBay activity. Notices sent to other users about suspicious activity and notice violations on our sites may refer to your public username and specific items. If you associate your name with your user ID, the people to whom you have revealed your name may then be able to identify your eBay activities.

To help protect your privacy, we allow only limited access to other users' contact, delivery and financial information as necessary to facilitate your transactions and collect payments. However, when users are involved in a transaction, they have access to each other's name, username, email address and other contact and delivery information.

### Your responsibilities over transactional information you receive through eBay

When you transact with another user, we enable you to obtain or we may provide you with the personal information of the other user (such as their name, account ID, email address, contact details, delivery and billing address) to complete the transaction. Independent from us, you are the controller of such data and we encourage you to inform the other user about your privacy practices and respect their privacy. In all cases, you must comply with the applicable privacy laws, and must give the other user a chance to remove them from your database and them a chance to review what information you have collected about them.

You may use the personal information that you have access to only for eBay transaction-related purposes, or for other services offered through eBay (such as escrow, delivery, fraud complaints, and member-to-member communications), and for purposes expressly consented by the user to whom the information relates. Using personal information of other users that you have access to for any other purpose constitutes a violation of our User Agreement.

### Unwanted or threatening email

We do not tolerate abuse of our Services. You do not have permission to add other users to your mailing list (email or postal), call, or send him/her text messages for commercial purposes, even if this user purchased something from you, unless the user has given his/her explicit consent. Sending unwanted or threatening email and text messages is against our User Agreement. To report eBay-related spam or spoof emails please forward the email to [spam@ebay.com](mailto:spam@ebay.com) or [spoof@ebay.com](mailto:spoof@ebay.com).

### Communication tools

We may scan messages automatically and check for spam, viruses, phishing and other malicious activity, illegal or prohibited content or violations of our User Agreement, this privacy notice or our other policies.

### Children's Privacy

Our websites are general audience websites and not intended for children. We do not knowingly collect personal information from users deemed to be children under their respective national laws.

### Third Party Privacy Practices

This privacy notice addresses only our use and handling of personal information we collect from you in connection with providing you our Services. If you disclose your information to a third party, or visit a third party website via a link from our Services, their privacy notices and practices will apply to any personal information you provide to them or they collect from you.

We cannot guarantee the privacy or security of your personal information once you provide it to a third party and we encourage you to evaluate the privacy and security policies of your trading partner before entering into a transaction and choosing to share your personal information. This is true even where the third parties to whom you disclose personal information are bidders, buyers or sellers on our site.

## Contact Us

If you have a question or a complaint about this privacy notice, our global privacy standards, or our information handling practices, you can reach the Global Privacy Office in writing at: eBay Inc., Attn: Legal - Global Privacy Office, 2065 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, California 95125, USA.

You can find more information on how to contact us and our data protection officers at our [eBay Privacy Center \- opens in new window or tab](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/).

### Handling your complaints

For more information on how your complaint will be handled, refer to the User Agreement.

Your right to file complaints with a data protection supervisory authority remains unaffected.
